KATHERINE JONES

Woodstock, GA 30188

Phone: 770-696-6480 Email: kejone1414@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/katherineetjones/ | Github: https://github.com/katjones23 | Portfolio: https://thedevkat.com/

SUMMARY

Adaptable and analytical Web Developer with a background in cloud-based platform administration and over 5 years of professional experience. Earning a Full-Stack Web Development certificate from Georgia Tech with skills in MERN. Proven ability to learn technical skills quickly while communicating it in an easy to understand language. Excellent critical thinking and analysis for problem solving and delivering solutions, taking ambiguous ideas to completed projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, SQL, Express, Handelbars.js &

ReactJS

Applications: Bootstrap, MySQL, MongoDB, GitHub

OTHER SKILLS

Agile methodologies, project life-cycles, vendor and client relationship management, presentation skills, product knowledge

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Rapidly stood up a solution for 8 hotlines, SMS lines, and emails for a 12-member team to adapt their roles in response to COVID-19.
- Served as the technical lead in an implementation of a new contact center solution used across multiple teams and departments that provided a more streamlined service for 300+ users.
- Continuous improvement and support of the company's use of software platforms, often as the single Subject Matter Expert.
- Developed, maintained, and improved SharePoint and Nintex forms and workflows to expedite processes touching multiple teams such as manual payouts and adding new job templates.

RECENT PROJECTS

Project Name: Recipe-Xchange

Description: "Recipe-Xchange" is a web app built with a group for saving and searching recipes with nutritional information calculated and provided.

Build information: Served as the back-end engineer with some support in the front-end as well. Utilizes user authentication and built with Sequelize, Node, Express, an API, and NPM packages.

https://github.com/AndreaGT91/Recipe-Xchange | https://recipe-xchange.herokuapp.com/

Project Name: EatDaBurger

Description: "EatDaBurger" is a web app for listing burgers to devour, and check off when they

have been devoured.

Build information: Created with MySQL, Node, Express, Handlebars, and an ORM with

Heroku for hosting.

https://github.com/katjones23/EatDaBurger | https://kat-jones-eatdaburger.herokuapp.com/

KATHERINE JONES

PAGE 2

Project Name: N2Movies

Description: "N2Movies" is a collaboratively developed web application that populates movie

recommendations based off of a movie name.

Build information: Served as a JavaScript developer and project manager. Built using

Materialize for the styling and data from two APIs.

https://github.com/katjones23/N2Movies | https://katjones23.github.io/N2Movies/

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Technical Specialist MarketSource

2017 – 2020 Alpharetta, GA

In addition to the responsibilities assumed under Systems Administrator:

- Collaborated with coworkers and other departments to enhance and optimize usage of current technologies.
- Served as the subject matter expert for multiple cloud-based applications used by the company.
- Developed and built forms and workflows to minimize repetitive and manual work.

Systems Administrator MarketSource

2016 – 2017

Alpharetta, GA

- Supported user requests and troubleshoot reported issues through the ticketing system.
- Developed solutions for internal teams wanting to begin use of or increase use of the contact center solution.
- Created reporting based off of the raw data provided by the platform, and assisted the Analytics team in enhancing the reporting.

Recruiting Specialist MarketSource

2016 – 2017 Alpharetta, GA

 Reviewed resumes for appropriateness of experience and knowledge in relation to position requirements

- Partnered with district managers to regularly establish rapport, gauge morale, and source new candidates
- Organized all pertinent applicant and interview data in the Applicant Tracking System (ATS)

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: Georgia Tech, Peachtree Corners. GA

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor's in Chinese Language and Literature: University of North Georgia, Dahlonega, GA **GPA:** 3.76/4.0

Awards & Honors: magna cum laude, Phi Kappa Phi, Psi Chi, Honors Program Graduate